I'm going to call the order of the regular meeting by the City Council for Monday, January 3rd, 2022.
Two public input and let's get to the first one.
I'm going to have three consent agenda staff recommendations.
We can approve item sport and five.
Thank you most of the group.
Second.
Perfect.
Five.
Six.
In a local agreement between the City of Miami and the Board of the County Commission.
One.
Okay.
This is the same resolution that has to be approved by both boards.
So.
Second.
Davis.
Five.
Eight.
Simburg.
High.
Double.
Upstate.
Parker.
Five.
Seven.
Joint Resolution.
2022.
That's your one of the mayor in the City Council of Miami.
So, how many of the Board of Trustees of Miami, especially each other?
Authority Board for community financial support and fee waiver to the momentary.
How's the authority in mind?
Tried to housing authority.
For the remodels, revations of the amount of towers and that tribe's towers within the City of
Miami.
I say I make a motion to do what we did in our last meeting of what Ben said.
Yes.
You can.
Someone.
I'll second.
E-step.
Five.
Simburg.
High.
Parker.
I have an opportunity to crossing the cross road
to the table, two.
Obviously.
Three.
Thirty.
Eight.
Two.
Three.
Five.
Four.
Three.
I need is for you to authorize the same managers, signature, so we can carry on this animal.
We need to draw employees to get them to participate.
Which we haven't got a separate 5% participation, right?
Because we have been wanting to participate to the longest part of what we've given the impact of the deductible as a credit,
which is part of the more helpful insurance to $700, like it will free in our $50 credit.
I'll make a motion to approve.
Hi.
He's that.
December.
Hi.
Davis.
Parker.
Hi.
Thank you.
I'm not in election resolution CC 2022-02 calling for and proclaiming an ordering in on-partisan
general election in the city of Myola County of Ottawa State of Oklahoma on Tuesday,
April 5 2022 for the purpose of electing the Council members for award 1 of the northeast and board 2 of the northwest.
I'll make a motion to approve.
Second.
This is this is simply something you have to do under the law in order to have the election when we're required to have it.
I have to stay for those in the third ward.
They do not have to do the same.
Hi.
December.
Don't vote.
Davis.
Is that time?
10.
The discussion regarding updating the ward boundary map after the US census.
Yeah.
So this is the bad news.
That's why we put it after that one.
The, as you all know last year, the national census was done.
But for a variety of reasons, the reason they primarily give is because of COVID.
The census bureau has not accomplished any of the things that they're supposed to have accomplished by this point in time.
So what that means for us is we cannot, we should be having a motion to modify our ward boundaries tonight.
So as to clarify if there's any changes of what those boundaries are going to be, particularly for wards 1 and 2.
But we can't do it because we don't have any of the information that is required.
And the statute says that we have to do it as soon as is reasonably possible.
But without the data from the census bureau, we don't have anything with which we can act.
Yet our election is required to be held pursuant in the timeframes pursuant to the resolution that you all just passed.
What that means is we use the same boundaries that we have right now.
And whether the two council members that hold those wards want to run for election or not, that's really irrelevant to what our problem is going to be.
Our problem is that when we get the elect election.
of the census data that we need, which according to the election board, our county election
board will be sometime after the election, then we have to go through the process of actually
making the word boundary changes.
So we don't know what that is going to do.
All of that to say, you know, and I'm not exactly sure we're either of you actually live
in your words, but there is a possibility, you can be drawn out of the word that you just
got elected to, or the two of you be put into the same word, or somebody that else that
wants to run could be changed out of the word that they just ran for, or whether they
want or not.
I mean, there's a number of possibilities.
Now, those are all remote possibilities, but you have to be aware that they are possibilities.
There are various restrictions on how we redraft those boundaries.
One is that the statutes require that we try our best to not split precincts.
Well, the precincts in Ottawa County have, for years, and been going through substantial changes.
Back when I first got involved in politics, there were 34 precincts in Ottawa County.
Today, there are 15, but soon there will only be 13.
And those changes are going to affect precincts in the city of Miami.
A thing that the county election board cannot do, cannot do, is they cannot split precincts
for county commissioner districts.
That didn't have any great relevance to us, although all I'm saying there is that kind of screws
up their process a little bit.
Our statutes say as we should try our best, not to split precincts for our ward boundaries.
What they're going to do with the changes that they're going to make, and these changes will be after the election.
So, none of these changes are going to affect what our election will actually do, but just so that you'll know precinct.
8 will be closed and the voters there will vote at precinct 7, which is southern hills, precinct 8 right now, is the first Baptist Church.
8 will be closed and those voters will vote in 7, which is southern hills, Baptist Church.
9 will be closed and that is all Saints Episcopal Church and those voters will then vote here at the Civic Center.
They're two blocks apart but they're right now, they're different precincts.
Then precinct 12, which is cutting-edge ministries, the polling places, cutting-edge ministries, will also be closed and those voters will vote at the Senior Citizen Center.
The complication for that one is precinct 12 is basically in Ward 2 and Senior Citizens Center is basically in Ward 1.
So, voters after this, now again, this is all after our election, but from here on out, voters will be voting at the same precinct, some for Ward 1 and some for Ward 2.
But all that is just telling you what future problems are going to be.
We have to sit down once we get the data from the census bureau, we have to go block by block and add up numbers so that each of the Wards end up having a relatively close number of.
So that each one of you or the person then holding your position will be representing approximately the same number of people as the others are represented.
None of that is a problem for the mayor because the mayor represents the entire city.
So, we just wanted to give you an update, explain to you why we're not redrafting the precinct lines.
Excuse me, the Ward lines at this point, we can't, that will be done sometime after the election and hopefully it does.
None of those possible problems will ever come to fruition.
So, what happens in life?
somebody gets elected to order one, and the change has happened, and that person no longer lives in
order one.
So our charter requires that the person representing the award actually has to live in the
award, and so that's going to present a support.
Now, can we figure out a way that we draw the lines where nobody changes the awards?
That's possible, but we can't get into some really squirrely looking jerry mandarin, or we get sued.
So it doesn't say anything that the person's even if they move, a lot of the finish
they're done.
And you're asking me a question that probably last week I could have answered for you.
And now that you mentioned that I think that that is correct.
I didn't get the provisions out of the charter.
I will get you that answer.
I don't care that right now.
I want to make sure I'm correct when I say that.
Okay, so we're going to relax with this.
No action.
We just wanted to update you.
We should have been presenting to you a resolution to re-graph the lines tonight.
But we can't.
So I want to explain why.
Thank you.
11.
Any other new businesses registered, posting this agenda?
12 staff reports?
13.
Mayor and council committee announcements.
Thank you very much.
Well, Amber has resigned.
And I want to personally thank you for all the help that you have done for me personally.
And from what I've seen you do, and it's minimizing.
And thank you very much for what you've done.
You've done a lot of good work.
I don't remember approving that.
I mean, they're going to still happen.
But I'll go ahead and jump in there with my.
because I was one of the things I wanted to mention.
Yeah.
Four teams.
So Amber has resigned.
And apparently it's rough to the meeting.
Yes.
That's her last action.
Can we make a motion to disapprove?
Yeah.
Sure.
Is that how you want us to win?
I mean, come on.
Amber has worked for the city for 11 years, 12 years.
Obviously, I've only been here for the last year.
And really, really sad to see her go.
Amber, as you all can imagine, coming into this position,
not only green to this position, but green to civic government, to municipal government.
And she has been a tremendous bridge in that morning.
She knows where all the skeletons are.
She knows wherever a piece of paper needs to go.
She knew when I needed to return a call.
And when she should be the one to return a call.
Because it would go much better.
She was usually right.
Just a tremendous wealth of information.
The girl can do just about any job in the city.
She probably wants to do.
But what says a lot about her integrity as a human.
Because she had been considering a move for some time.
And I happen to say that.
But she had been considering to move at some time.
And when COVID hit, she knew that wasn't the right time to leave her appointment.
Because the city needed her.
And then when they hired a new city manager, as green to Zion,
she knew that wasn't the right time.
And she stuck around for her fellow employees for me.
And just did a tremendous job at helping me get settled in and my feet under me.
And I just can't say enough about Amber and what she's done, how hard she works, her integrity.
And we're losing her to a tribe that I hope they realize what they're getting.
And I think they probably do.
Amber can do about whatever Amber wants to do.
And I think she's been on a climb within her own career for the last several years.
If there's anything that I've heard many, many times for many, many people,
when I come in and talk about Amber and what she's done for me,
they say, oh, but if you would have seen the changes that she has made in her career,
that from where she started, the growth that she has shown within this entity has been tremendous.
And I'm sorry that I didn't get to see that, but I'm proud of her all the same.
Because so many people have mentioned that, I know it to be true.
And I just commend her on what she's done in fur, for every.
for you all included. I know you all know this. She's always been to go to. Anyway, with that,
Amber, thank you. Thank you from the bottom of my heart for all that you've done for me. Thank you for
all that you've done for the City of Miami. And thank you for all that you've done for the citizens
within this entire community. And you are very civic minded. And for that, I just can't order you enough
and what you've done. And I'm proud of you and I know I know what I'm excited for you, what you're going to do.
And we have a fantastic ally that's going to one of our tribe. So there's nothing you could ask for more than to
have someone leave your appointment. It's good of standing as she does. Knowing that she'll continue to be there for us.
Time will allow. We won't bug her during your work day, but that institutional knowledge still resides there in a
friend that we may have to leave her so it's hope's fall.
I hope. I hope. Thank you for all of you. You deserve many accolades. The only other thing I wanted to take a minute to
mention to you, I'll probably more of the song for note. Please keep Amanda Davis and her family and your thoughts and
prayers. Her father is having some pretty significant health issues and is in the hospital now and I see you and
is really struggling, I believe. And so please keep her and your thoughts and prayers and just think about her and
her family. I'm sure it's a very tough tough time right now for them but we all miss her but we all
support her and she knows that she and I have talked multiple times today and she knows that
family first and that's the way it should be. She acts as a son and doesn't mean that I read that.
So please continue to break on because she's been strong but she needs us to lean on 15 adjournment.
Go ahead.